<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dashboard on </title>
    <link>https://oakestra.io/docs/dashboard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dashboard on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://oakestra.io/docs/dashboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Start your Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://oakestra.io/docs/dashboard/getting-started-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 09:56:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oakestra.io/docs/dashboard/getting-started-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://oakestra.io/wiki-banner-help.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dashboard is a sophisticated web-based user interface for the Oakestra system.&#xA;It is designed to provide users with a comprehensive set of tools to deploy applications to a&#xA;Oakestra cluster, effectively manage cluster resources, and troubleshoot any issues that may arise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the Dashboard, users can gain an insightful overview of the applications currently running on&#xA;their cluster. It allows them to create and modify individual services,&#xA;view the status of running services, and configure service-level agreements (SLAs) with an intuitive form.&#xA;This feature-rich interface also enables users to monitor the state of Oakestra resources within&#xA;their cluster and track any errors that may have occurred.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access Control</title>
      <link>https://oakestra.io/docs/dashboard/access-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 09:56:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oakestra.io/docs/dashboard/access-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://oakestra.io/wiki-banner-help.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;access-control&#34;&gt;Access control&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Upon successful installation and accessibility of the Dashboard, our attention can shift to configuring&#xA;access control to resources for various users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Upon launching the framework for the first time, an administrative user is automatically generated.&#xA;This administrative user can then be leveraged to create additional users and organizations within the system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Credentials for the admin user:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Username:&lt;/strong&gt; Admin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Password:&lt;/strong&gt; Admin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that after the initial launch of the System Manager,&#xA;it is imperative to change the password for the Admin user as an added measure of security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>https://oakestra.io/docs/dashboard/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 09:56:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oakestra.io/docs/dashboard/features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://oakestra.io/wiki-banner-help.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The user interface is still under development and therefore does not offer so many features yet.&#xA;However, we are working on it to support more and more features.&#xA;If you find ideas for new features or bugs post an issue in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oakestra/dashboard&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-an-application&#34;&gt;Creating an application&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Oakestra there is the principle of applications and services, within one application there can be several services and one user can create several applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
