<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> – Contribute</title>
    <link>https://oakestra.io/docs/contribute/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contribute on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://oakestra.io/docs/contribute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Contribution Guide</title>
      <link>https://oakestra.io/docs/contribute/contribution-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 10:39:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oakestra.io/docs/contribute/contribution-guide/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;oakestra-contribution-guide&#34;&gt;Oakestra Contribution guide&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oakestra&amp;rsquo;s codebase is open-source on GitHub and open to &lt;strong&gt;external&lt;/strong&gt; contributors as well. The purpose of this guide is to help the developer contribute in such a way that both people directly involved in Okaestra and people outside the research group can follow what happens within the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each contribution starts from an issue on the corresponding repository. E.g., Are you willing to update the front end? Open an issue on the dashboard repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue can be of two kinds: &lt;strong&gt;Proposal&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Bug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Template for &lt;strong&gt;Proposal&lt;/strong&gt; issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;short&#34;&gt;Short&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short description of what you&amp;rsquo;re proposing. Max 2 lines. Highlight if this is something new or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re willing to change some specific behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;proposal&#34;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description of the modification you&amp;rsquo;re proposing. You can have references, links, and images. Please be very specific here. External contributors must be able to understand the context and the goal of the proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ratio&#34;&gt;Ratio&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short description of why this is important&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;impact&#34;&gt;Impact&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the components that potentially need to be touched. E.g., Root service manager, Cluster scheduler, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;development-time&#34;&gt;Development time&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expected time required to complete the development of this proposal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;status&#34;&gt;Status&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the current status of this proposal. E.g., looking for feedback, searching for a solution, development, and testing. Try to be concise but descriptive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;checklist&#34;&gt;Checklist&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Discussed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Documented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Implemented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Tested&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Template for &lt;strong&gt;Bug&lt;/strong&gt; issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;short-1&#34;&gt;Short&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short description of the bug you noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;proposal-1&#34;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deeper description of the bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, propose a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;status-1&#34;&gt;Status&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Describe the current status of this proposal. E.g., looking for feedback, searching for a solution, development, testing. Try to be concise but descriptive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;checklist-1&#34;&gt;Checklist&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Discussed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Solved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Tested&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;issue-names&#34;&gt;Issue names&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to be concise and informative. Here some good ✅ and bad ❌ examples to give you an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scheduling  ❌&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of LDA to Cluster Scheduler ✅&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frontend edit ❌&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frontend cluster management panel ✅&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think we need to replace the login token with a new JWT token ❌&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JWT API authentication ✅&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contribution-steps&#34;&gt;Contribution steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open an Issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting from the issue, detach a branch from &amp;ldquo;develop&amp;rdquo; and entitle it using the following pattern: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Issue nr.&amp;gt;_issue_name_in_snake_case&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform your contributions in this branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to update the documentation as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the PR passes all the automated tests suits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once finished, open a Pull Request towards the develop branch. If you&amp;rsquo;re a student, put your supervisors as Reviewers. Otherwise, refer to the people with the most contributions. Then wait for their approval.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;multi-repo-contributions&#34;&gt;Multi-repo contributions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The codebase is split into multiple repositories. Sometimes a single contribution might need to span across some of them in parallel. This is where things get tricky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributions spanning multiple repositories are difficult to track and require careful management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please open multiple issues, one for each repository, and cross-link them. Each issue discusses only the modification required on that specific repository but links to the issues embedding the work required elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a general rule, is better to perform the merges in parallel.
Make sure to open the pull requests together and cross-link the other pull requests between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-work-into-issues&#34;&gt;Your work into Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to find out the single tasks of your workflow and open up the corresponding issues accordingly.
Breaking down the work into issues makes it easier to merge and test the features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N.b.&lt;/strong&gt; Always assign the issue to yourself and maybe indicate if this is part of a specific milestone, thesis, or guided research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discuss-with-the-community&#34;&gt;Discuss with the community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the growth in the interest for Oakestra, many people are onboarding. By collaborating on this project, you have the chance to ask for their ideas as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to write the issues in a clear way so that anyone might be able to fit in and contribute.
Then keep an eye on the issue&amp;rsquo;s comment section and add the label &amp;ldquo;help needed&amp;rdquo; if required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;versioning&#34;&gt;Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project version is written in the file &lt;code&gt;version.txt&lt;/code&gt;
Make sure to update this file accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N.b. The versions are amanged only by this file. NEVER CREATE A VERSION TAG MANUALLY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-images&#34;&gt;Release images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An accepted pull-request towards main creates a release TAG corresponding to the version in &lt;code&gt;version.txt&lt;/code&gt;.
The release images will be created automatically by the git workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a release tag exist already, will not be replaced. You need to increase the version number!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you get an artifact creation error, most likely the release was not yet created on github. Please create a new release for the new tag and re-run the failed jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alpha-images&#34;&gt;Alpha images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An accepted pull-request towards develop creates an alpha TAG corresponding to the version in &lt;code&gt;version.txt&lt;/code&gt; with the &lt;code&gt;alpha-&lt;/code&gt; prefix. If the tag exists already, it will be updated.
The alpha images will be created automatically by the git workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you get an artifact creation error, most likely the release was not yet created on github. Please create a new alpha-release for the new tag and re-run the failed jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://oakestra.io/docs/contribute/coc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 15:56:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oakestra.io/docs/contribute/coc/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;contributor-covenant-code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-pledge&#34;&gt;Our Pledge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interest of fostering an open and welcoming environment, we as
contributors and maintainers pledge to make participation in our project and
our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body
size, disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression,
level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal
appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-standards&#34;&gt;Our Standards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of behavior that contributes to creating a positive environment
include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using welcoming and inclusive language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being respectful of differing viewpoints and experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gracefully accepting constructive criticism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focusing on what is best for the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showing empathy towards other community members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of unacceptable behavior by participants include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of sexualized language or imagery and unwelcome sexual attention or
advances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trolling, insulting/derogatory comments, and personal or political attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public or private harassment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing others&amp;rsquo; private information, such as a physical or electronic
address, without explicit permission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other conduct which could reasonably be considered inappropriate in a
professional setting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Our Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project maintainers are responsible for clarifying the standards of acceptable
behavior and are expected to take appropriate and fair corrective action in
response to any instances of unacceptable behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project maintainers have the right and responsibility to remove, edit, or
reject comments, commits, code, wiki edits, issues, and other contributions
that are not aligned to this Code of Conduct, or to ban temporarily or
permanently any contributor for other behaviors that they deem inappropriate,
threatening, offensive, or harmful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Code of Conduct applies within all project spaces, and it also applies when
an individual is representing the project or its community in public spaces.
Examples of representing a project or community include using an official
project e-mail address, posting via an official social media account, or acting
as an appointed representative at an online or offline event. Representation of
a project may be further defined and clarified by project maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enforcement&#34;&gt;Enforcement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instances of abusive, harassing, or otherwise unacceptable behavior may be
reported by contacting the project team at [INSERT EMAIL ADDRESS]. All
complaints will be reviewed and investigated and will result in a response that
is deemed necessary and appropriate to the circumstances. The project team is
obligated to maintain confidentiality with regard to the reporter of an incident.
Further details of specific enforcement policies may be posted separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project maintainers who do not follow or enforce the Code of Conduct in good
faith may face temporary or permanent repercussions as determined by other
members of the project&amp;rsquo;s leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Code of Conduct is adapted from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org&#34;&gt;Contributor Covenant&lt;/a&gt;, version 1.4,
available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/code-of-conduct.html&#34;&gt;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/code-of-conduct.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For answers to common questions about this code of conduct, see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/faq&#34;&gt;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/faq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
